Guide to the George Tinkham Papers, 1909-1952
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
George Tinkham papers 1909-1952
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Tinkham, George Holden.
10.4 Linear Feet 631 Items
U.S. representative from Mass.
Chiefly clippings and press releases relating to the life of George Holden Tinkham, a lawyer, Republican senator, and big game hunter from Boston, Mass. Tinkham's political career is well represented by the clippings and press releases (1919-1942), which show his position on foreign and domestic affairs, and detail his opposition to the prohibitionists.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The George Tinkham Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a deposit in 1977.
Biographical Note
George Holden Tinkham was a Representative from Massachusetts; born in Boston, Suffolk County, Mass., October 29, 1870; attended the public and private schools; was graduated from Harvard University in 1894; member of the Boston Common Council in 1897 and 1898; studied law at Harvard Law School; was admitted to the bar in 1899 and commenced practice in Boston; member of the Board of Aldermen, 1900-1902; served in the State senate 1910-1912; served overseas during World War I; elected as a Republican to the 64th Congress and to the thirteen succeeding Congresses (March 4, 1915-January 3, 1943); was not a candidate for renomination in 1942; continued the practice of law in Boston, Mass., until his retirement; died in Cramerton, N.C., August 28, 1956; interment in Forest Hills Cemetery, Boston, Mass.
Biographical note is excerpted from the Biographical Dictionary of the United States Congress.
Collection Overview
Chiefly clippings and press releases relating to the life of George Holden Tinkham, a lawyer, Republican senator, and big game hunter from Boston, Mass. Tinkham's political career is well represented by the clippings and press releases (1919-1942), which show his position on foreign and domestic affairs, and detail his opposition to the prohibitionists.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Tinkham, George Holden
United States -- Congress -- House -- History -- 20th century
Legislators -- United States
Prohibition -- United States
United States -- Politics and government -- 1901-1953
United States -- Foreign relations
Massachusetts -- Politics and government
Scrapbooks
Contents of Collection
- Papers, 1909-1952, (4 boxes)
  - Correspondence, 1916-1952 (Box 1)
  - Press releases, 1919-1942
  - Writings, 1914-1942
  - Election returns, 1909-1940 (Box 2)
  - Miscellany
  - Clippings
  - Printed materials
  - Small volumes (Box 3)
    Bound volumes with contested elections, Louisiana sugar prices investigation (1920), and campaign expense reports.
  - Voting records: House of Representatives, 65th-77th Congresses (Box 4)
- Oversize Volumes, 1915-1942, (8 volumes)
  - Clippings, 1915-1920 (Volume 1)
  - Clippings, 1920-1923 (Volume 2)
  - Clippings, 1923-1926 (Volume 3)
  - Clippings, 1926-1929 (Volume 4)
  - Clippings, 1929-1930 (Volume 5)
  - Clippings, 1930-1941 (Volume 6)
  - Clippings, 1938-1942 (Volume 7)
  - Records, 16th Congress, 1st session, 1916-1918 (Volume 8)